Hello, everyone.
Witam wszystkich.
Yayoi Squad has made contact with Hirokawa.
Oddział Yayoi znalazł Hirokawę.
Do not let him get away. Eliminate him.
Nie pozwólcie mu uciec. Wyeliminujcie go.
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
Well, don't just stand around. Take a seat.
Nie stójcie tak. Usiądźcie.
&lrm;SEX AND SPIRIT
SEKS I DUSZA
You could say your victory in this incident is assured.
Wasze zwycięstwo jest niemal pewne.
When it comes to killing,
Kiedy chodzi o zabijanie,
nothing on Earth can match the human race.
nic na Ziemi nie może równać się z ludźmi.
However, the tools you currently hold should be put to different use,
Jednak narzędzia, którymi dysponujecie,
for a purpose far greater.
mogłyby zostać wykorzystane w lepszej sprawie.
They should be used to protect the balance of the biosphere.
Powinny służyć ochronie biosfery.
That should be your intended mission.
To powinna być wasza misja.
In a word, culling.
Ubój.
All of humanity will realize soon enough
Wkrótce zrozumiemy,
that human numbers must be reduced immediately,
że liczba ludności musi zostać ograniczona.
that the crime of pollution
Zanieczyszczanie środowiska jest gorszą zbrodnią niż morderstwo.
and that our existence is of such great importance
Wydaje się nam, że nasze życie jest tak ważne,
You should place greater value on your predators.
Nie doceniamy drapieżników.
And these particular predators
A ci konkretni drapieżnicy
fit perfectly into the beautiful hierarchy of nature!
idealnie wpasowują się w hierarchii natury.
They fit right above humans!
Tuż ponad ludźmi.
This will restore the balance at last.
Wreszcie przywrócą równowagę.
Hirokawa.
Hirokawa.
Someone on Earth had a sudden thought.
Ktoś na Ziemi pomyślał:
"Life must be protected."
„Musimy chronić życie”.
Just who do you think you are? You monster!
Za kogo ty się masz, potworze?
This is why I can never like humans.
I dlatego nie lubię ludzi.
If defiance is your final answer, don't pretend otherwise at the start.
Jeśli zamierzacie działać w przekorze, nie udawajcie, że jest inaczej.
Environmental conservation measures
Programy ochrony przyrody są tworzone tylko z myślą o ludziach.
Why do you refuse to acknowledge that?
Czemu tego nie przyznacie?
Prioritize the prosperity of all life over that of the human race!
Myślcie o całym życiu na Ziemi, nie tylko o ludziach!
That is what would make you the superior species!
Tylko to dałoby wam wielkość.
You fools claim justice is on your side!
Twierdzicie, że jesteście po stronie sprawiedliwości.
But what greater justice is there than this?
Lecz nie ma sprawiedliwości ponad selekcję naturalną.
We inhabit humans
Już nie rasa ludzka odpowiada za równowagę na tej planecie.
In comparison, humans are the true parasitic vermin infesting this planet!
Teraz to wy jesteście szkodnikami tej planety!
Or should I say…
A raczej...
Parasitic beasts?
zarazą.
Parasitic beasts.
Zarazą?
Fire!
Ognia!
What's the matter?
Co jest?
This is a human.
To człowiek.
What?
Co?
Hirokawa.
Hirokawa.
An inscrutable man until the very end.
Pozostał zagadką do samego końca.
Tamura Reiko was greatly intrigued by this human
Ten człowiek intrygował Tamurę Reiko.
and made many plans on his account,
Wiązała z nim wiele planów,
but they are all finished now.
ale to już koniec.
He must have appeared unusual in your eyes as well,
Dla was też musiał być nadzwyczajny.
for a human.
Jak na człowieka.
Unbelievable.
Niewiarygodne.
What could've…
Co tu się stało?
Like I said, it's that guy we just saw.
To robota tego faceta.
He has incredible power.
Ma ogromną moc.
Even firearms are useless against him.
Broń palna jest tu bezużyteczna.
-What is it? -Hirokawa has been neutralized,
- Tak? - Hirokawa zneutralizowany,
but a new parasite seems to have appeared.
ale pojawił się nowy pasożyt.
We will rendezvous with the Minazuki Squad and head for the council wing.
Udajcie się do skrzydła rady z oddziałem Minazuki.
Uragami.
Uragami.
You bastard.
Ty gnoju.
Man, my arm's all numb.
Ręka mi zdrętwiałą.
I prefer knives.
Wole noże.
Oh, wow, it blew his hand right off.
Kurczę, rozwaliło mu całą dłoń.
Of course this is how things would end, Detective.
Mógł się pan tego spodziewać, detektywie.
Either way, I was on death row, wasn't I?
Byłem skazany na śmierć.
I'm going to get out of here!
Wydostanę się stąd.
If that monster is as good as I think he is,
Jeśli ten potwór naprawdę jest taki potężny,
he's sure to break the cordon.
z pewnością przerwie kordon.
Come to think of it, Tamura Reiko often asked
Przypominam sobie, że Tamura Reiko często pytała,
for what purpose we have come into existence.
jaki jest cel naszego istnienia.
It's of no concern to me now,
Teraz to dla mnie bez znaczenia,
but I have realized one thing.
ale zrozumiałem coś.
I live only to fight.
Żyję tylko, aby walczyć.
Shinichi, let's go home.
Shinichi, wracajmy do domu.
There's no point in staying here any longer.
Pozostawanie tu nie ma sensu.
We have fulfilled our purpose.
Już się na nic nie przydamy.
You don't know that for sure.
Nie możesz być pewien.
We still have to figure out whether Gotou can be defeated.
Wciąż musimy ustalić, czy Gotou można jakoś pokonać.
It doesn't matter.
To bez znaczenia.
The humans have won.
Ludzie wygrali.
If they want to, they can use cannons, missiles, napalm balms,
Mogą używać dział, rakiet, napalmu, wszystkiego.
What we might want to do as individuals
To, czego chcemy my, nie ma już znaczenia.
You're acting weird, Migi.
Dziwnie się zachowujesz, Migi.
Fire!
Ognia!
How's he moving like that?
Jak on to robi?
Fight smarter.
Walczcie mądrzej.
Humans are supposed to be the most intelligent beings on the planet,
Ludzie są rzekomo najinteligentniejszym gatunkiem na planecie.
He's dodging gunfire!
Unika kul.
I don't just dodge.
Nie tylko unikam.
I can use a shield, too.
Mam też tarcze.
Don't shoot.
Nie strzelajcie!
Fire.
Ognia. Już im nie pomożemy.
Shit, that agility of his.
Cholera, jest naprawdę zwinny.
Being indoors limits our firing options
Walcząc pod dachem mamy ograniczone możliwości
and we risk friendly fire.
i nie widzimy, do kogo strzelamy.
We need to be somewhere more open.
Potrzebujemy otwartej przestrzeni.
Retreat.
Odwrót.
To the roof. The roof, now!
Na dach!
One more round.
Jeszcze jeden.
-Didn't that round finish him? -Don't let your guard down.
- To go nie wykończyło? - Bądźcie czujni.
We will exercise due caution and engage the enemy on the roof.
Wznowimy walkę na dachu.
He can navigate walls and ceilings as well as any floor.
Potrafi poruszać się po ścianie i suficie.
Indoor combat tactics are useless against him.
Wewnątrz nie mamy z nim szans.
This is his lair,
Jesteśmy w samym sercu jego kryjówki.
How ironic that we have lost our advantage
To ironia losu. Ma nad nami przewagę w miejscu zbudowanym przez człowieka.
All right, scatter to both sides!
Obstawcie obie strony.
We'll engage him here!
Wznowimy tu walkę.
What are you talking about?
Co ty pleciesz?
Impossible.
Niemożliwe.
You're the only one left.
Zostałeś sam.
I cleared out the men behind you.
Dorwałem twoich ludzi.
Or perhaps saying I "scattered them" would be more appropriate.
A raczej rozerwałem na strzępy.
How do you even work?
Jak ty to robisz?
Don't tell me that your body's also…
Czy twoje ciało jest…?
That's right.
Tak.
But I have not armored my entire body.
Ale nie jestem cały opancerzony.
There are gaps.
Mam słabe punkty.
I was somewhat careless in this fight, given your sheer firepower.
Byłem dość nieuważny w trakcie tych walk.
Even if I harden my cells,
Choć moje komórki są wzmocnione,
deflecting gunshots head-on is not without risk.
taka osłona nie jest pozbawiona ryzyka.
That's why I deflect them at an angle, like this.
Dlatego trzymam tarczę pod kątem.
You dare mock me?
Kpisz ze mnie?
Also, though I dodge gunfire,
Unikam kul, ale nie jestem od nich szybszy.
I predict the direction of fire based on the opponent's eye and hand movements.
Przewiduję kierunek ognia, obserwując oczy i ręce przeciwnika.
What was that sound?
Co to za dźwięk?
I think it came from the roof.
Dochodzi z dachu.
Who the hell are you?
Kim ty jesteś?
I'm what you see.
Przecież widzisz.
I'm just a wild organism.
Jestem dzikim organizmem.
An organism?
Organizmem?
And what are humans, then?
A czym są ludzie?
Organisms.
Organizmami.
A flamethrower, huh?
Miotacz płomieni, co?
Maybe that isn't such a bad idea.
Może to jednak dobry pomysł.
Hey, something just fell out of the sky.
Coś spadło z nieba.
What's wrong?
Co jest?
I told you so.
Mówiłem ci.
Oh, you again.
Znowu ty.
Gotou.
Gotou.
I see.
Rozumiem.
So you were also involved.
Byłeś w to wmieszany.
It was a large battle, to be sure.
To była wielka bitwa.
It seems all the others have been killed,
Cała reszta zginęła.
and you were a part of it.
Maczałeś w tym palce.
The job is not yet finished.
To jeszcze nie koniec.
Killing you should bring me closure.
Zabijając cię, zaznałbym spokoju.
That's right. I should kill you.
Tak, powinienem cię zabić.
Then I will move forward.
I posuwać się naprzód.
"Forward"?
„Naprzód”?
Not a bad aim, if you were going for the heart.
Niezły strzał, jeśli celowałeś w serce.
Impossible.
Niemożliwe.
Let's finish this later.
Dokończymy to innym razem.
There is too much interference,
Teraz jest tu za duży ruch, a ja jestem zmęczony.
He flew!
Jakby latał!
Izumi-kun, what exactly are you?
Izumi-kun, kim ty jesteś?
I don't know!
Nie wiem!
I have no idea!
Naprawdę nie wiem!
Wait!
Czekaj!
We suffered heavy casualties.
Odnieśliśmy poważne straty.
The majority were men under Yamagishi's command,
Większość ofiar służyła pod Yamagishim.
and all it took was one monster to turn the tables on us.
To wszystko sprawka jednego potwora.
Can you truly claim you knew nothing about this?
Twierdzisz, że nic o tym nie wiesz?
You're hiding something again, aren't you?
Znowu coś ukrywasz, prawda?
I don't know!
Nie miałem pojęcia, że mogą być aż tak potężne.
A head!
Głowa!
Someone's head just fell from the sky!
Czyjaś głowa spadła z nieba!
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
Shinichi, that was quite a nightmare.
To był dopiero koszmar.
How do you know what I dreamed about?
Skąd wiesz, co mi się śni?
It's just a feeling.
Czuję to.
Will Gotou come for us?
Gotou spróbuje nas dopaść?
He most definitely will, and soon.
Na pewno, i to niedługo.
I sensed his resolve.
Czułem jego determinację.
So I guess we're going to die.
A więc zginiemy.
We can't give up that easily.
Nie możemy się poddać.
We should get help.
Poprośmy kogoś o pomoc.
Uda, for example.
Na przykład Udy.
No. We can't drag them into something like this.
Nie możemy ich w to wciągać.
Humans, then.
To zwróćmy się do ludzi.
We'll pit military forces against him again.
Wyślemy na niego wojsko.
How?
Nawet gdybyśmy mogli, zginęłoby przez to mnóstwo osób.
And we'll be the ones responsible for their deaths!
Bylibyśmy za to odpowiedzialni.
I couldn't care less.
Trudno.
Migi.
Migi.
You never change, Migi.
Nic się nie zmieniasz.
Dad, I might have to say goodbye soon.
Tato, być może będę musiał się pożegnać.
Mom, I might be able to see you again soon.
Mamo, być może wkrótce się zobaczymy.
Hey, why don't we run somewhere far away?
A może gdzieś ucieknijmy?
Not even Gotou is so obsessed with us that he'd follow us all over Japan, is he?
Gotou nie będzie nas ścigał po całej Japonii, prawda?
Migi.
Migi.
Are you asleep?
Śpisz?
Oh, I forgot to go to school.
Zapomniałem iść do szkoły.
School.
Szkoła.
Wait, he's asleep?
Czy on śpi?
Migi?
Migi?
If he attacks now…
Jeśli zaatakuje teraz…
Apologize.
Przeproś.
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
Wow, he's scared shitless.
Ale się boi.
Say it on your knees.
Na kolana.
Sorry.
Bardzo przepraszam.
I apologized, didn't I?
Przecież przeprosiłem!
I apologized!
Przeprosiłem!
I apologized, okay?
Przeprosiłem, okej?
Izumi-kun.
Izumi-kun.
Hey.
Hej.
Oh, did you skip school today?
Znowu nie poszedłeś do szkoły?
Yeah.
Tak.
I did. I'm a cheat, you know.
Jestem niepoważny.
I'm a loser.
Jestem nieudacznikiem.
What's wrong?
Co się stało? Dziwnie się zachowujesz.
Hey.
Hej…
Stop. You're hurting me.
Przestań. To boli.
Please let go.
Puść mnie.
Stop!
Przestań!
Izumi-kun.
Izumi-kun!
Your idea to run far away may not be a bad one, Shinichi.
Ucieczka może być całkiem niezłym pomysłem.
Oh, you were awake?
Nie spałeś?
Far away, huh?
Gdzieś daleko.
And I'm so close to graduating.
Niedługo kończę szkołę.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
Have your senses become dull?
Osłabiły ci się zmysły?
Hello.
Cześć.
How did you know I'd be here?
Skąd wiedziałaś, że tu będę?
You like parks, Izumi-kun.
Lubisz parki, Izumi-kun.
I can tell because I like them, too.
Wiem, bo sama je lubię.
Sorry about earlier.
Przepraszam za wcześniej.
I didn't mean to frighten you.
Nie chciałem cię przestraszyć.
You're a strange guy, Izumi-kun.
Dziwny z ciebie chłopak, Izumi-kun.
I sometimes don't think I know you at all.
Czasem myślę, że w ogóle cię nie znam.
Don't you think it's cold out here?
Zimno tu.
Come over to my place.
Chodź do mnie.
Let's talk.
Porozmawiajmy.
No one else is home today.
Nikogo nie ma w domu.
When you feel your life's on the line, your true nature surfaces.
W obliczu śmierci na wierzch wychodzi twoja prawdziwa natura.
I'm so pathetic.
Jestem żałosny.
All I can think about is how I don't want to die.
Myślę tylko o tym, że nie chcę umrzeć.
I want to live.
Chcę żyć.
I want to keep on living.
Chcę żyć dalej.
I've called Migi cold-blooded a lot,
Oskarżałem Migiego o bezwzględność,
but I don't have any right to say that.
ale nie mam do tego prawa.
In the end, I'm trampling over those around me in order to live.
Sam krzywdzę wszystkich wokół siebie, aby przeżyć.
Shinichi-kun.
Shinichi-kun.
You're really pretty amazing.
Jesteś niesamowity.
We've gone through a lot together,
Wiele razem przeszliśmy,
We can't lose.
Nie przegramy.
Satomi, I like you a lot.
Satomi, bardzo cię lubię.
I love you.
Kocham cię.
Izumi-kun,
Izumi-kun,
you always drop quiet bombshells like that at the end.
ty to wiesz, kiedy mówić takie rzeczy.
I'm going to live.
Przeżyję.
No matter what it takes!
Za wszelką cenę!
Next time, "Quiescence and Awakening."
Następny odcinek: „Sen i przebudzenie”.